I have folks let's take a peek at a game
我有伙计让我们看一下游戏
now where we can begin to see whether
现在我们可以开始看看是否
iterative elimination of strictly
严格消除迭代
dominated strategies has any bite in
主导策略有任何影响
application and in order to do this
应用程序并为此
we're gonna look at an experiment that
我们要看一个实验
was done by Baldwin and Meese in the
由Baldwin和Meese在
late 1970s and they were actually
1970年代后期，实际上
looking at social behavior in pigs so
看猪的社会行为
this the players in our game here are
这是我们游戏中的玩家
going to be pigs and there's actually a
会是猪，实际上有一个
sort of an interesting discussion of
有点有趣的讨论
this this comes from Joe Harrington's
这是乔·哈灵顿的
book game strategies and decision-making
预定游戏策略和决策
and the idea is sort of interesting
这个想法很有意思
you've got two pigs in a cage okay so
你在笼子里有两只猪好吧
they're in a cage several meter caged
他们被关在几米的笼子里
one of the pigs is larger than the other
一只猪比另一只大
we call that the dominant Pig or I mean
我们称主要猪或我的意思是
well sorry for the terminology so what
不好意思，所以该怎么办
we'll actually use the word larger Pig
我们实际上将使用更大的猪这个词
and in what they need to do is is food
他们需要做的就是食物
arrives but they need to press a lever
到达，但他们需要按一下操纵杆
to get the food to arrive okay and the
拿到食物就可以了
critical thing is that the lever is on
关键是杠杆已经打开
one side of the cage you go over you
笼子的一侧，你越过你
press the lever and then the food
按下控制杆，然后按下食物
arrives on the opposite side of the cage
到达笼子的另一侧
okay so the pigs are put in a cage the
好吧，所以把猪放在笼子里
cage they learn eventually that if they
笼子里，他们最终了解到，如果他们
hit this lever food appears on the other
打这个杠杆食物出现在另一个
side so what they would have to do is if
一边，所以他们将要做的是
they want to eat they would have to move
他们想吃东西，他们不得不搬家
over a run up to one side of the cage
越过笼子的一侧
hit the lever run back to the other side
撞到另一边
get the food that comes out eat the food
得到出来的食物吃的食物
a few pellets of food then they go back
几粒食物然后回去
hit the lever again run back to the
再次击中操纵杆
other side of the cage get some food
笼子的另一边吃些食物
okay now the difficult part is that
好吧，现在困难的部分是
there are two pigs in the cage so if we
笼子里有两只猪，所以如果我们
put two pigs in the same cage and one is
将两只猪放在同一个笼子里，一只是
larger than when they're both trying to
比他们俩都想
get the food which comes out and and
得到出来的食物，然后
these are pigs the larger one will end
这些是猪，更大的会结束
up getting the food and the smaller one
拿起食物和较小的食物
will get less food okay so that's the
会减少食物的摄入量，所以这就是
basic idea here and then we can analyze
这里的基本思想，然后我们可以分析
this as a game
这是一个游戏
so in particular let's take a look in
所以特别让我们来看看
more detail at how the payoffs work here
有关收益如何工作的更多详细信息
so when the food comes out there's 10
所以当食物出来的时候有十个
units of food and say pellets of food
食物单位并说食物颗粒
that come out and let's look at what the
出来，让我们看看
typical split ends up being if there are
典型的分裂最终是如果有
two pigs in the cage one it's larger one
关在笼子里的两只猪，一只更大
smaller and if the larger one gets to
较小的，如果较大的
the food first then there's basically a
首先是食物，然后基本上是
1 9 split so that means that the small
1 9分裂意味着小
pig ends up with just with one pellet
猪只剩下一粒
and the larger pig would end up with 9
而较大的猪最终会得到9
units of the food so if the large one
食物的单位，所以如果大一个
gets there first it's very hard for the
首先到达那里对于
small one to get anything they tend to
小家伙得到他们倾向于得到的任何东西
get one on average but not close to
平均得到一个但不接近
nothing if the small Pig gets to the
如果小猪去了就没有
food first then they end up with a 4 6
食物，然后他们最终得到4 6
split ok so then it's 40 60 so the small
好的，然后是40 60那么小
pig still gets less the the bigger
猪仍然变得越来越少
people gets more but the small Pig at
人们得到更多，但小猪在
least has a literally a fighting chance
至少有一个真正的战斗机会
here now if they get to the food at the
如果他们现在在这里吃饭
same time then it's a 3 7 split so the
同时是3 7分割，所以
bigger Pig gets the little more and one
较大的猪多一点一点
other thing is that you know running
另一件事是你知道跑步
over and pressing the lever actually
并实际按下操纵杆
consume some calories so let's take that
消耗一些卡路里，所以让我们
they take it to say two units of food in
他们说这是两个单位的食物
terms of energy ok so so we've got these
能源条件还可以，所以我们有了这些
different splits and so forth so what we
不同的分裂等等，所以我们
can do is write out a simple normal form
可以做的就是写出一个简单的范式
game for that so given all these numbers
鉴于所有这些数字
here's the small pig over here large pig
这是小猪，这是大猪
over here and now they have two choices
在这里，现在他们有两个选择
they can either run over and press the
他们可以跑过去然后按
lever and or they could sit there and
杠杆，或者他们可以坐在那里
sit by the food side and wait for the
坐在食物边，等待
other Pig to press the lever
其他猪按下操纵杆
now if you both go to press the lever
现在，如果你们两个都去按操纵杆
then they get back to the food at the
然后他们回到那里的食物
same time it's going to be a three seven
同时它将是三七
split but it's a three seven split and
拆分，但这是三七拆分，
then you subtract off two for the cost
然后你减去两个
of running back and forth so they each
来回奔跑，所以他们每个人
lose two units of food so three minus
失去两份食物，所以减去三分
two we get the 1 7 minus 2 we get the 5
两个我们得到1 7减去2我们得到5
so we end up with 1 5 if they both do it
因此，如果他们俩都这样做，我们最终得到1 5
at the same time
与此同时
in a situation where say the small pig
在说小猪的情况下
presses the lever and the big pig just
按下杠杆和大猪只是
waits there then it's a 1 9 split but
等那里然后是1 9拆分，但是
the small pig ends up losing two units
小猪最终损失了两个单位
and energy they actually end up with a
和能量，他们实际上最终以
net negative in that situation and so
在那种情况下净负
forth so you can go through and put this
出来，所以你可以通过并把这个
into a normal form game what we end up
变成普通形式的游戏，我们最终会得到什么
with is a simple matrix form 2x2 game
与是一个简单的矩阵形式的2x2游戏
which looks like this okay so we can
看起来像这样，所以我们可以
analyze this game quite simply let's
简单地分析这个游戏，让我们
take it and let's say I analyze it via
拿它，说我通过分析
the iterative elimination of strictly
严格的迭代消除
dominated strategies so what's true in
主导策略，那么什么是正确的
this game well where does anybody have a
这个游戏很好，有人在哪里
strictly dominated strategy the big pig
严格控制策略的大猪
the large Pig doesn't have a strictly
大猪没有严格
dominated strategy they would like to
他们想主导的策略
wait if the other one presses they would
等对方按一下
prefer to press if the other one waits
如果对方等待，则喜欢按
so no domination here but notice that
所以这里没有统治，但要注意
the small pig always gets a higher
小猪总是更高
payoff for versus 1 0 versus minus 1
相对于1 0与相对于1的回报
they would always prefer to wait so in
他们总是喜欢等
this particular situation the small Pig
这种特殊情况的小猪
has a strictly dominated strategy of
有严格的策略
waiting so we should get rid of press as
等待，所以我们应该摆脱新闻
a strategy for the small Pig and once
小猪的策略，一次
we've done that now in what's left the
我们现在在剩下的
Big Pig should press and so what we end
大猪应该压，所以我们要结束
up with is when we iteratively eliminate
与我们迭代消除时
strictly dominated strategies we end up
最终被严格控制的策略
with a prediction that the small pig
预测那只小猪
should wait and the big pig should be
应该等待，大猪应该
the one that presses the lever okay so
按下杠杆的那一个好吧
let's look at how they actually behaved
让我们看看他们的实际表现
the pigs in there in the experiment and
实验中的猪
so what they did here is they gave him
所以他们在这里所做的就是他们给了他
15 minutes of doing this they did 10
15分钟的时间他们做了10
tests where the pigs were alone in the
测试猪只在哪里
cage so the first you ten tests where
笼子，所以第一个十测试
the pig just sits there for 15 minutes
猪只坐在那里15分钟
and learns how to to press the lever and
并学习如何按下控制杆和
get food and then they put the pigs
得到食物，然后他们放猪
together and do another 10 tests each
一起做另外10个测试
for 15 minutes as well okay so what
15分钟也可以
they're doing here is this is the
他们在这里做的就是这个
frequency of pushing
推送频率
lever per 15 minutes and we can look at
每15分钟一杆，我们可以看看
what happens when the large pigs are
当大猪是
when the pigs are separated they're both
当猪分开时，它们都是
alone there we see roughly the the large
一个人在那里，我们大致可以看到
pigs going about 75 times per 15 minutes
猪每15分钟走75次
and pressing the lever I mean these pigs
然后按下操纵杆，我的意思是这些猪
are really moving back and forth to get
真的来回移动以获得
the food the small pigs say 70 times
小猪说的食物70次
running back and forth to get the the
来回奔跑以获得
food so they're both if they're left
食物，如果他们都离开了，他们俩都是
alone they go they press the lever they
他们一个人走他们就按下操纵杆
run back and forth if they're together
他们在一起时来回奔跑
then what happens well the prediction
那么预测会发生什么
was that the larger Pig should do the
是更大的猪应该做的
pressing right they should do the
向右按他们应该做的
pressing and these smaller pigs should
紧迫，这些较小的猪应该
do the waiting and indeed how frequently
等待，实际上是多久一次
do they push the lever is the small pigs
他们推杆是小猪吗
very seldomly only 5 times now whereas
现在很少只有五次
the large pigs are doing it about 105
大猪大约要做105
times so indeed we are see them seeing
的确如此，我们确实看到他们看到了
them pressing and waiting in conjunct it
他们紧紧地等待着
by the theory and in fact the large pics
通过理论，实际上是大照片
are doing more pressing and partly
在做更多的紧迫和部分
possibly because they're getting fewer
可能是因为他们越来越少
pellets out since the small pig is
因为小猪是
sitting nearby and and eating some of
坐在附近，吃一些
the pellets that the large pig is
大猪的颗粒
producing by pressing the levers okay so
按下杠杆就可以制作
what do we learn from this our pigs
我们从猪身上学到什么
rational do they know game theory well
他们是否很了解博弈论
they probably didn't sit down and solve
他们可能没有坐下来解决
the the normal form game and it would
正常形式的游戏，它将
definitely eliminate strictly dominated
绝对杜绝严格控制
strategies but one thing is true is they
策略，但事实是它们是一回事
do learn and they did seem to respond to
确实学习了，他们似乎确实回应了
incentives and in and I think the
激励措施和在，我认为
iterative elimination of strictly
严格消除迭代
dominated strategies is something which
主导策略是
nicely captures learning so you learn
很好地捕捉学习，让您学习
not to play a strictly dominated
不要扮演严格的统治者
strategy right because it's always
策略正确，因为它总是
giving you a lower pay off eventually
最终给您较低的回报
discards such strategies so players
放弃这样的策略，所以玩家
won't be sitting there playing a
不会坐在那里玩
strictly dominated strategy if they ever
如果他们曾经严格控制策略
have some experience with other
有其他经验
strategies once they stop playing knows
他们停止比赛后的策略知道
then you learn not to play strictly
那么你就会学会不严格地玩
dominated strategies out of what remains
剩下的主导策略
so the small pig can learn that it just
这样小猪就可以知道
doesn't pay to run over and press the
不用花钱跑过去然后按
lever because the
杠杆，因为
Pig gets everything so they stopped
猪得到了一切，所以他们停了下来
pressing the lever they just sit there
按下杠杆，他们就坐在那里
and wait and eventually the big pig does
等一下，最后那头大猪
the pressing so you learn not to play
紧迫，所以你学会不玩
strictly dominated strategies out of
严格控制策略
what remains and and so the idea here is
还有什么，所以这里的想法是
that learning evolution survival of the
学习进化的生存
fittest these are powerful game
优胜劣汰，这些都是强大的游戏
theoretic tools and iterative
理论工具和迭代
elimination of strictly strictly
严格淘汰
dominated strategies in games where
游戏中的主导策略
there is some power to these things ends
这些事情有一定的力量终结
up you know making some predictions
你知道做出一些预测
which can be quite powerful
可能非常强大